with the SAT coming up a lot of people
have asked me about this exact type of
question I found this cool video going
over an example the tricky thing here is
we want to get X alone so when we're
done we should have x equals something
the thing people struggle with is how do
we get X alone when there's two x's so
let's watch the video and see how it's
done hey guys this looks like a fun one
it says solve for x it's 2x over 3 Pi +
the quantity 1 - x/ 2 = 0 if you want to
try it on your own pause it right now
cuz I'm going to solve it in three 3 2 1
first thing I don't really like
fractions so let's get rid of these
denominators and we're going to do that
by multiplying everything by the least
common denominator in this case between
3 pi and 2 6 Pi is the least common
denominator so we're going to multiply
everything by 6 Pi for this first term 6
Pi * 2x is 12 pi x and it's still going
to be divided by 3 pi and then for this
part the 6 Pi is going to distribute to
both of these so we're going to have two
separate fractions divided by two for
the first one 6 piun * 1 is equal to 6
piun and then we're going to subtract
and 6 piun * X is 6 piun x and on the
right hand side 0 * 6 Pi is still 0er
now we can simplify things to get rid of
the denominators for this first term the
two pies will divide each other out and
12 / 3 is equal to 4 for this term 6 / 2
is equal to 3 and for this term 6 / 2 is
equal to 3 now we have 4x + 3 piun - 3
piun x = 0 since we're trying to solve
for x we want all the terms that contain
X on one side and all the terms that do
not contain X on the other side so we
want to move this 3 pi over to the other
side and we can do that by subtracting 3
PI from both sides we can copy this down
and simplify 3 Pi - 3 Pi will go to 0
and 0 - 3 Pi is - 3 Pi now on the left
hand side every term contains an X let's
factor out that X when we Factor an X
Out of 4X we're left with four and then
we can bring down the subtraction and
when we Factor an X out of 3 pi x we're
left with 3 pi and we're still equal to3
Pi now to get X by itself we can divide
both sides by 4 - 3 pi and let's copy
this step down and simplify it on the
left hand side the 4 - 3 Pi on top and
bottom will divide each other out we're
left with X is equal to -3 pi over 4 - 3
Pi this is probably fine as an answer
but you can still kind of simplify it on
top we can factor out a negative 1 so
instead of -3 Pi we have -1 * 3 pi and
on bottom we can also factor out a 1 so
1 * what gives us 4 well that's -4 and
then -1 * what gives us -3 Pi well
that's positive 3 Pi now this might look
even more complicated but these two
negative ones will divide each other out
and now we can get rid of these
parentheses and rearrange it like this
so I don't know which one do you prefer
-3 pi over 4 - 3 Pi or 3 pi over 3 Pi -
4 I think this one looks a little bit
neater let's put a box around it the
question asks us to solve for x so this
is the answer to our question how
exciting